{
    "id": "ac2691bcc6024d89a734373fc1357d46",
    "title": "Nouns And Pronouns Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "This is one of the best novels that ……………….. appeared this year.",
            "description": "The verb in the relative clause should agree with the number and person of the antecedent of the relative pronoun.",
            "answers": [
                "has",
                "have"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "50080c5cd8b74188b746b6efb3d3d957"
        },
        {
            "question": "The boy …………………….. I trusted proved worthy of my confidence.",
            "description": "The boy proved worthy of my confidence.\r\nI trusted him.\r\nThe relative pronoun whom replaces words like him, her and them. When we combine them we use whom instead of him. ",
            "answers": [
                "who",
                "which",
                "whom"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "168bcb0758e840de8500afbe60d76eac"
        },
        {
            "question": "Ambition is one of those passions that ………………………. never satisfied.",
            "description": "The verb in the relative clause should agree with the number and person of the antecedent of the relative pronoun.",
            "answers": [
                "is",
                "are"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "3651928ceaf64336af7c52732e9b520f"
        },
        {
            "question": "This is the same man ……………………….. we saw yesterday.",
            "description": "When the antecedent is same, the consequent should be as or that.",
            "answers": [
                "that",
                "as",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "d5418be933214e3eb452d7d25607570f"
        },
        {
            "question": "He has an impudence ………………………… carry him through anything.",
            "description": "When the relative pronoun is the subject of the relative clause, it cannot be omitted.",
            "answers": [
                "would",
                "which would",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "6e899ad90df143bb8f46f9f4a55dbd15"
        },
        {
            "question": "You and ………………………. are invited to tea this morning.",
            "description": "A pronoun used as the subject should be in its subject form.",
            "answers": [
                "I",
                "me",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "1fea791c748648ec92bb018b88b921c7"
        },
        {
            "question": "Are they better qualified than ………………………… to judge?",
            "description": "Subject pronouns are not normally used after than if it is not followed by a verb.",
            "answers": [
                "we",
                "us",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "2fc87e7287134763a304098ce2d44704"
        },
        {
            "question": "Neither of them ………………………….. invited to the party.",
            "description": "The distributive pronouns each, either and neither are followed by a singular verb.",
            "answers": [
                "was",
                "were"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "fe9f66763a8e4576a6b952f9f3d4b3a3"
        },
        {
            "question": "The athlete, ……………………………. you spoke so highly of, has failed to qualify for the race.",
            "description": " The athlete has failed to qualify for the race. You spoke so highly of him. \r\nThe relative pronoun whom replaces words like him, her and them.",
            "answers": [
                "who",
                "which",
                "whom"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "b1feb986940446029d8238dc33c3f146"
        },
        {
            "question": "When you have examined these documents please return ………………………. to us.",
            "description": "Avoid the use of same as a substitute for the personal pronoun.",
            "answers": [
                "same",
                "them",
                "the same"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "d058de7df6414058a8c33e7264b74f34"
        },
        {
            "question": "They know it as well as ……………………… do.",
            "description": "Here the pronoun I is the subject of the verb do. ",
            "answers": [
                "I",
                "me"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "ca8bc73e610a4d3db58e87b323ead001"
        },
        {
            "question": "He is as good a bowler as ....................................",
            "description": "After as and than we can use an object pronoun or a subject pronoun + verb. ",
            "answers": [
                "me",
                "I am",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "f7402ed155a3428d82fec88b50ed1620"
        }
    ]
}